JENNIFER LINDSEY

Irvine, CA 92618 Email: jlindsey010@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/jJLindsey</u>010 | GitHub: <u>https://github.com/JJLindsey</u>

Portfolio: https://jjlindsey.github.io/portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Art and a dedication to life-long learning. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Experience in collaborating to create and deliver materials that are accessible to all audiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, jQuery

Applications: GitHub

Other: Git, Command Line, MVC, Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator, Microsoft Office Suite

PROJECTS

State of the Art

https://github.com/JJLindsey/ArtFiles2 https://state-of-art.herokuapp.com/

- Full stack Application designed to allow museums and similar institutions to add, search, and edit location of artwork. By signing up through app, the user can then add title, artist, date, medium, style and location of their institutions artwork.
- Responsibilities incl: creating the dataset, writing CSS, Handlebars framework.

Brewed Force

https://github.com/JJLindsey/brewed-force

https://takes101.github.io/globe-trotting-and-bar-hopping/

- Website designed to unite the beer minded traveler with new breweries and beers in new cities. By entering a city into the search feature, the user will be met with a list of breweries in that city.
- Responsibilities: write CSS for application and JavaScript for local storage.
- JavaScript/HTML/CSS/Material Design Lite

EXPERIENCE

Museum Educator | Kimbell Art Museum | 2019 - June 2020

Work collaboratively with fellow museum educators to create and present interactive gallery & studio art programs using the elements & principles of art. Modeled critical thinking to connect audiences to works of art within the permanent collection. Researched artworks within collection to keep lessons within cultural & historical context.

Yoga/Meditation Instructor | Mindful Pose | 2012 - present

Teaching hatha yoga, mindful flow, yoga nidra and meditation classes in corporate and private sessions. Providing a safe & supportive environment for all levels of practitioners

Art History Professor | Southern New Hampshire University | 2013 - 2015

Taught Modern Art, Art History and Art Appreciation courses in an online environment, engaging students through discussion board and article reflections, & journals.

Visual Thinking Strategies Internship | Boston MFA | 2012

Observed teachers in the classroom to facilitate discussions of visual art to increase student engagement, performance, and enjoyment of learning. Scored, transcribed essays for database for research of teaching critical thinking skills in a classroom setting.

Coordinator | Hope Cottage | 2010 - 2011

Designed a state-wide marketing campaign for non-profit, mobile media ad. Created & implemented Client Management Database for reporting. Developed, wrote, and edited database manual for staff.

EDUCATION

Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN

Bootcamp Certificate:A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Courtauld Institute of Art, University of London, London, England MA – Art History

University of Texas, Arlington, TX BA – Art History and French, Summa Cum Laude

Additional Skills

Critical thinking and analysis
Presentations and public speaking
Excellent communication skills
Strong writing skills
Competent in adapting content for diverse audiences
Intensive research
Problem-solving and decision-making
Attention to detail
Organization
Time management
Ability to work independently or in teams
Aesthetic and design consciousness
Creativity